

Varvara Lazarenko

Address
Telephone
E-mail
Date of birth

LinkedIn

Nijmegen, The Netherlands +31 6 2662 9839

E-mail varlazoa@gmail.com **of birth** 29.12.1998 (26 years)

www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly motivated and hardworking graduate with a Master's degree in Medical biology. Having worked in fundamental research setting as well as in clinical trials development, I am passionate about societal aspects of healthcare innovations. With a strong biomedical foundation and a keen interest in sustainable healthcare, I envision a career in health technology assessment (HTA), value assessment, health economics, healthcare education or consultancy.

EDUCATION

09/2022 - 08/2024

MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA 7.63/10.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Reaching the Sustainable Development Goals
- ✓ <u>Projects</u>: «HTA of a Medical Guidance App for International Students in the NL» «A Shared Ownership Model of the Green Corridor, Nijmegen» «A Circular Alternative to Single-Use Cups Within the Dutch Train System»
- ✓ <u>Master thesis</u>: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care»

09/2016 - 06/2020

BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Physiology of secretory system, Introduction to endocrinology
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats»

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2024 - 08/2024

Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care

HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- √ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023

Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory

Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- √ In vivo Ca²⁺ imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (mice, handling & feeding)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

08/2021 - 08/2022 Assistant at the Science department of the Contract Research Organization LABMGMU, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- √ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

10/2020 - 10/2021

Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological and molecular biology experiments (wire myography, real-time PCR, western blot)
- √ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at two conferences (Oct, 2020; Apr, 2021)

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, and MS Office softwares

LANGUAGES

Russian (native), English (fluent – C_2), German (intermediate – B_1 - B_2), Dutch (low intermediate – A_2 - B_1), French (beginner - A_1)

ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

2022-2024	Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
2020-2021	Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
2021	Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

CERTIFICATES

2023	A course on ex. Art. 9 of the Dutch Act on animal experimentation, Radboudumc
2021	An upgrade training on ICH GCP guidelines, LABMGMU

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY

2024	Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
2023	Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
2022-2023	Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
2018-2021	Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

HOBBIES

Volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., **Lazarenko Varvara S.**, Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. *Frontiers in physiology*, *13*: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- **2. Lazarenko Varvara**, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. *Artery Research*, *26*(S1): S58. https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., **Lazarenko V.S.**, Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. *Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina*, *54*(2): 89–95. https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639